<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Be My SpaceTime - blog</title><link href="https://avinal.space/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://avinal.space/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://avinal.space/</id><updated>2021-01-04T21:47:00+05:30</updated><subtitle>눈치</subtitle><entry><title>HRT Systems Internship Interview Experience</title><link href="https://avinal.space/posts/blog/hrt-interview-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-01-04T21:47:00+05:30</published><updated>2021-01-04T21:47:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Avinal</name></author><id>tag:avinal.space,2021-01-04:/posts/blog/hrt-interview-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;I applied for &lt;strong&gt;Systems Internship - Summer 2021&lt;/strong&gt; back in December 2020 at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.hudsonrivertrading.com"&gt;Hudson River Trading&lt;/a&gt; , New York.....Questions were clear and of medium level. But they were designed in such a way that you must know the basics before you could attempt.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I applied for &lt;strong&gt;Systems Internship - Summer 2021&lt;/strong&gt; back in December 2020 at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.hudsonrivertrading.com"&gt;Hudson River Trading&lt;/a&gt; , New York. The internship description was: -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for highly motivated students who are eager to learn and excited about systems to join us for our summer internship
program. As a systems intern, you may have the opportunity to work on projects in the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming/scripting (Golang, Python, C++, C)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FOSS development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HPC, Cluster computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;System Administration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux, Debian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux-based computer security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large deployment or config management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step was a coding test on the Codility platform. If you have used any of the online coding platforms, this is similar. It was a &lt;abbr title="90 mins"&gt;2.5 hrs&lt;/abbr&gt; test consisting of 3 questions. They let you use &lt;abbr title="documentation, man pages, etc."&gt;online references&lt;/abbr&gt; but
&lt;strong&gt;do not copy the code&lt;/strong&gt; as it will highly reduce your chances of qualifying for this first stage. You can choose between &lt;strong&gt;C/C++&lt;/strong&gt;,
&lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Golang&lt;/strong&gt; (no Java 😪).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions were clear and of medium level. But they were designed in such a way that you must know the basics before you could attempt.
Also, they expected a clear and concise approach. Two of the most important points in their instructions were: -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While correctness and performance are the most important factors for evaluation, we will take test duration into account as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please understand that this test is meant to be challenging. A perfect score is not necessary to move on to future interview rounds, so do the best you can!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you must be near perfect in your approach as well as on time. I did them kind of quickly. They will show you a summary of your
submission but not the results. It will take almost 2 weeks to get back to you for further steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I received a mail invitation for a telephonic interview. &lt;strong&gt;This interview will last about 45 minutes and will be technical but will not require coding. Interview topics may include your background, programming languages, and Unix/Linux concepts&lt;/strong&gt;. Once you receive this
mail you can then decide a time slot for an interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not sure what they will ask if this is not a coding interview. The interviewer was very polite, and he was explaining the questions
too. Questions were not so tricky but practical and real-life. Since it was &lt;strong&gt;not for SDE role&lt;/strong&gt;, the questions were mostly related to
Linux/Unix, C++ (mainly pointers and memory), Python/Bash scripting, automation, knowledge of tools (IDEs, Editors, System Administration
Tools) and previous experiences. The interview would often explain why he is asking this question, this was very nice. Then some common
interview questions, why do you want to work for this role? What makes you fit for this role? etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that I want to point out is that the interviewer was repeatedly checking my resume, and for the most part he did not ask
anything that was not on my resume. So, my tip is to create a nice resume with genuine work/tool experiences. And when you are applying
for such a role, it would be helpful if you mention mathematics or other courses that you have taken. &lt;em&gt;Do not lie on your resume&lt;/em&gt;. They
will easily catch that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other thing is to keep your words short and clear; I was not great at communication, but you can be. If the interviewer allows then
use examples for the things you cannot explain. I used nice examples. At last, he gave me short feedback on how well I performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last, I want to point out things I should not have done. The first is, I did not ask much about the role, you must do this at least
once. Second, I am talkative, I do not know if the interviewer was not faking his expressions (because he would often discuss in-depth),
but not all interviewers will be the same. So, do not talk too much, nor too less. At last work on your communication skill, mostly how
you to present things and how to answer technical as well as behavioral questions. I was not fluent, but my way of presentation might
have saved me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="blog"></category><category term="HRT"></category><category term="hudsonrivertrading"></category><category term="interview"></category><category term="internship"></category></entry><entry><title>The Interstellar Twilight</title><link href="https://avinal.space/posts/blog/this-is-for-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-28T22:47:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-28T22:47:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Avinal</name></author><id>tag:avinal.space,2020-09-28:/posts/blog/this-is-for-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;If in the Twilight of dreams we should meet once more, we shell talk again together and I shall sing to you a lullaby till you sleep again to meet me in the Twilight of another dream.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it was a dream someday. I never imagined you. But I do remember glimpses of a wonderful person
in my deep slumber. When I go back to last year about the same time, I find myself a manic who gets
carried away with every emotion. Becoming too happy about something and then becoming too sad was so
common that I never noticed what I was risking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;If in the Twilight of dreams we should meet once more, we shell talk again together and I shall sing to you a lullaby till you sleep again to meet me in the Twilight of another dream.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But 1 year ago many things changed. A never seen dream came true. To be honest I was skeptical if all
this happening to me was true. Even until last December. Gradually things started falling into places.
And for the most part, the reality became more real. I can now easily see what is happening and why it
happened. Everything was so nice until we had a fight. Then another, and now it was every other day
story. It was a really hard time collecting everything together and act as nothing happened after every
single of those. Everything was plunging. I started imagining the end of something that I did not
imagine to happen in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But during all those times, there was a continual intuition that maybe there is something that we both
are missing. And that was maybe the root of all chaos. I never came to know that what it was neither did
you. But I do realize many mistakes I have been doing since we met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank you for not losing hope in me. We both always tried to reduce tension as much as we could.
And thank you for many other ineffable things happened because of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of now I can see things making sense. Every message, every talk now seems to make sense. I am more
deeply into this friendship if I was not ever before. The ecstasy of having you is other-worldly. I don't
know if I could ever adore a person this much but I adore this ravishing friendship. Only you or only
this friendship may mean nothing to me. But I am delighted to say that I have both and I have you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, what is all with The Interstellar Twilight. Why this name ? Let me explain it for you. &lt;strong&gt;Interstellar&lt;/strong&gt;
means between stars and &lt;strong&gt;Twilight&lt;/strong&gt; means the soft glow when the sun is below the horizon.
&lt;strong&gt;The Interstellar Twilight&lt;/strong&gt; means the glow between the stars or simply glow of a cluster of stars. A
single star shines but the glow is too low to be noticed against its brightness. But a lot stars together
gets a glow. So my friend we are such two stars and our friendship is that glow.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="blog"></category><category term="interstellar"></category><category term="twilight"></category></entry></feed>